sabanow.net 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy

Last Revised September 29, 2016

This Policy applies to Saba Software, Inc., and its affiliated entities throughout the world (collectively referred to as “Saba,” “we,” or “us.”). Saba is committed to protecting your personal information. For that reason, Saba created this Policy which explains what personal information Saba collects about you, the purposes for which it uses and shares this information and how we safeguard that information. If you do not agree to the privacy practices described in the Policy, please do not use "www.saba.com" or related sites (collectively, the “Site”).

If you have any questions or complaints regarding this Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us at [legal@saba.com](mailto:legal@saba.com). If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Saba’s privacy practices described herein comply with the APEC Cross Border Privacy Rules System.  For more information, please visit:  <http://www.apec.org/Groups/Committee-on-Trade-and-Investment/~/media/Files/Groups/ECSG/CBPR/CBPR-PoliciesRulesGuidelines.ashx>

Saba Software, Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.  Saba is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

Saba is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  Saba  complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data receivedortransferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Saba is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  In certain situations, Saba may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor Framework**

Saba Software, Inc. complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from Switzerland. Saba Software, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Saba Software, Inc.’s certification, please visit  <https://safeharbor.export.gov/swisslist.aspx>.

**What this Policy Applies To**

The personal information covered by this Policy (“Personal Information”) includes, but is not limited to, personal information that is collected online at the Site and personal information that Saba receives from its clients pertaining to contractors, customers and related parties of the clients ((a) and (b) collectively referred to as "Users").

**Collection of Personal Information**

Saba collects Personal Information such as names, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses and birth-dates. For example, if you submit a webinar registration to us online, we will collect your e-mail address. If you use Saba’s software through one of our clients, you may be asked to input information into an individual profile. This profile may include your name, registrations, certifications, qualifications, Saba Meeting sessions attended, employment information and/or other information. Users may also be asked to select a password. We also collect Users' names, companies, industries, postal addresses, email addresses and/or phone numbers when they register to receive certain information from us and/or our Site. Personal Information collected by Saba may be stored in the US or any other country in which Saba or its agents maintain facilities.

We receive permission to post written and video testimonials that include personal information prior to posting on our Site.

If you use our blogs on this Site, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.

Our blog is managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want your personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

On occasion, we have access to sensitive Personal Information of Users provided to us by clients located in the EU and/or in Switzerland. This sensitive Personal Information may include racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, financial records, health information, sexual orientation and/or alleged commission of an offense. Saba will not disclose such sensitive Personal Information to a non-agent third party or use it for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized, unless the individual explicitly consents or a legal exception applies.

**Use of Personal Information**

Saba uses Personal Information to:

  * Confirm and fill orders for products and services;
  * Assist clients with learning and people management requirements,  and collaboration sessions;
  * Perform professional services;
  * Administer accounts and provide support;
  * Maintain databases and subscription lists;
  * Process job applications;
  * Update databases;
  * Alert Users to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new or complimentary products and services;
  * Deliver services, such as newsletters, events, training and software requested by Users;
  * Create and publish content relevant to Users;
  * Provide Users with access to limited-entry areas of our Site as appropriate;
  * Otherwise conduct its business operations; and
  * Contact Users as necessary for the above purposes.

We will not use Personal Information for any other purpose incompatible with the purposes listed above, unless it is required or authorized by you, is in your own vital interest or is necessary to comply with a legal obligation. Your Personal Information may be shared with Saba business affiliates in a manner consistent with the Policy.  At any time, if you do not wish your Personal Information to be shared with any Saba business affiliates, please contact Saba Legal by clicking [here](mailto:privacy1@saba.com). With respect to Personal Information provided by clients, Saba uses such Personal Information solely for the purposes of performing tasks on behalf of, and under the instruction of, our clients as their service provider.

**Use of Personal Information by Third Parties**

Personal Information may be shared with third party agents who provide products and/or services to Saba and it customers, such as web site hosting, information technology consulting, web site management, foreign language support, complementary products and services requested by Users, data analysis, audit, legal, administrative, back-up, security, marketing and promotion. Saba works to ensure that such third parties use the Personal Information only for the purposes for which we engage them (or our customers request of them)  and under similar privacy protection to what we maintain.

In the event there is a change in Saba's corporate structure, including, without limitation, merger, consolidation, sale, liquidation or transfer of substantial assets, Saba may, in its sole and absolute discretion, transfer, sell or assign information collected, including, without limitation, aggregated information and Personal Information, to one or more affiliated or unaffiliated third parties, as part of such restructuring.  Any affected Users will be notified via our Site or email.  Saba may also retain and disclose Personal Information in order to: (1) comply with applicable laws; (2) respond to governmental inquiries or requests; (3) comply with valid legal processes; (4) protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of Saba, Site visitors, clients or the public; (5) enforce our Site terms of service; and (6) permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

**Direct Marketing**

By submitting information on the Site, Users may receive promotional email updates about products and services related to their requests.  If, at any time, you would like to discontinue receiving any such email updates, you may unsubscribe by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each promotional email.  

**Third Party Promotions**

We may also ask Site Users to choose whether to allow Saba to share their Personal Information with third parties for marketing purposes. We will honor the choices made. If you subsequently decide that you no longer wish to receive promotional emails from Saba, or if you no longer wish to allow Saba to share your Personal Information on a going-forward basis for marketing purposes with third parties, you may opt-out of receiving such emails or from such sharing as described below in the Access and Correction section.

We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you opt-out as described above, we will not be able to remove your Personal Information from the databases of third parties with which we have already shared your Personal Information (i.e., to which we have already provided your Personal Information as of the date that we implement your opt-out request). If you wish to cease receiving marketing-related emails from such third parties, please contact such third parties directly or utilize any opt-out mechanisms set forth in their respective privacy policies or marketing-related emails.

**Use of “Cookies” and Other Tracking Technologies**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Saba and our online marketing affiliates. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Site, tracking users’ movements around the Site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to simplify visitors’ access and to tailor our services to visitors’ needs and interests. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our Site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our Site may be limited.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality. 

We use Local Storage also referred to as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Site or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity use Local Storage to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LS’s.

**Behavioral Targeting/Re-Targeting**

We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/))  Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

**External Links**

The Site may include links to other web sites not controlled by Saba. Please note that we are not responsible for the collection, use, maintenance, sharing, or disclosure of data and/or information by such third parties. Once you leave our Site (you can usually tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. That policy may differ from ours. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of web sites that you visit before submitting personal information. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of these web sites via a link from the web site's homepage, you should contact the web site directly for more information.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Site includes Social Media Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site. These Widgets may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the Widget to function properly. Social Media Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Widgets are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Single Sign On Feature**

You can log in to our job portal using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect. These type of service will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form.  Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.   

**Security and Confidentiality**

Saba takes appropriate and commercially reasonable technical and organizational measures to protect Personal Information against unauthorized access, accidental loss or damage and unauthorized destruction. Saba employees who handle confidential, proprietary or personal information are required to treat it confidentially and are not permitted to use it for purposes unrelated to Saba's business or disclose it to unauthorized third parties.

For online financial transactions, we do not perform any nor collect any related personal information that you transmit to us via our Site. Unfortunately, however, no security system or system of transmitting data over the Internet can be guaranteed to be entirely secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please notify us of the problem by contacting us at privacy1@saba.com.

**Data Retention**

We will not keep Personal Information longer than as necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes outlined herein. We seek to avoid the retention of unnecessary or duplicative information.

**Data Integrity**

Saba takes reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Information it maintains is reliable for, and relevant to, its intended use. We also endeavor to ensure that such Information is accurate, complete and current.

**Access, Deletion and Correction**

Where required by applicable law, Saba provides Users with the right to access, delete and correct their Personal Information that Saba holds and controls. For information about how to exercise these rights, or to unsubscribe from our newsletters, or if applicable, from our continuing to share information with third parties for their marketing purposes, please contact Saba Customer Service by clicking [here](mailto:privacy1@saba.com) or by writing to us at the below email address. We will respond to all requests for access within 30 days.

**Policy Updates**

We may update this Policy from time to time. When we do so, changes in our Policy will be effective immediately upon posting the revised Policy to the Site. If you are a regular visitor to this Site, we recommend that you check this Policy on a regular basis. By continuing to use the Site after a revised Policy has been posted, you will be deemed to have agreed to Policy changes. If you do not agree with the terms of this Policy, please do not continue using this Site.  If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

Changes to this Policy will be posted on the Site "[www.saba.com/us/privacy-policy/](http://www.saba.com/us/privacy-policy/)". You should visit the Site periodically to review the most recent Policy.

**Contact Information**

Questions regarding this Policy should be directed to Saba at [legal@saba.com](mailto:legal@saba.com) or by contacting us at:

Saba Software, Inc.  
Attn: Legal Dept.  
2400 Bridge Parkway  
Redwood Shores, CA 94065  
USA
